Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Kathryn and today we're going to play a game.
我是Kathryn，今天我们要玩一个游戏。
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going to describe someone's face.
今天我们要描述一个人的脸。
So we're going to try to guess who that person is.
所以我们要试着猜出那个人是谁。
Okay, so there are lots of really great words to describe people's faces in this lesson.
好的，这节课有很多很棒的词可以用来描述人的脸。
Let's take a listen to today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment to talk about what's
我们来听听今天的对话，稍后我们会回来讨论一下
going on.
发生了什么。
Let's play a game.
我们来玩个游戏吧。
Okay, how about Scrabble?
好啊，玩拼字游戏怎么样？
No, no.
不，不。
A friend of mine taught me this really fun game.
我一个朋友教了我一个很好玩的游戏。
I'm going to describe someone's face and you guess who it is.
我来描述一个人的脸，你来猜是谁。
Okay.
好的。
Let's see.
让我想想。
He has a Roman nose, bushy eyebrows, and dimples.
他有一个高挺鼻、浓密的眉毛和酒窝。
Our cousin Pete.
我们的表弟皮特。
My turn.
轮到我了。
He has a pointy nose, sunken eyes, and a mole on her chin.
他有一个尖鼻子、凹陷的眼睛，下巴上有一颗痣。
Aunt Rose.
罗斯阿姨。
That mole is so huge.
那颗痣真大。
Okay, my turn.
好了，轮到我了。
He has a crooked nose and full lips.
他有一个歪鼻子和丰满的嘴唇。
He has quite a few freckles and an oval face.
他有很多雀斑，脸是椭圆形的。
Oh, he's also bald.
哦，他还是个秃头。
Your future husband.
你未来的老公。
Not funny.
不好笑。
All right, we're back so now let's take a look at five key words that we have to describe
好了，我们回来了，现在来看看在“语言小贴士”环节中，我们用来描述
someone's face on Language Takeaway.
人脸部的五个关键词。
Language Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
So we've got a couple words for noses here.
我们这里有几个描述鼻子的词。
They're adjectives to describe noses.
它们是描述鼻子的形容词。
The first one that we heard is Roman nose.
我们听到的第一个词是“高挺鼻”。
Okay.
好的。
So if someone has a Roman nose, does that mean they're from Rome?
如果有人有“高挺鼻”，那意味着他们来自罗马吗？
No, not quite.
不，不完全是。
Well, Rome as we know is a city in Italy but it's also an adjective here.
嗯，我们知道罗马是意大利的一个城市，但在这里它也是一个形容词。
Roman means that the nose is straight on top.
“高挺”意味着鼻子顶部是直的。
It's like a triangle.
它像一个三角形。
Okay.
好的。
But it's kind of long.
但它有点长。
You have kind of a long straight nose, right?
你有一个有点长而直的鼻子，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
A very long straight nose.
一个非常长而直的鼻子。
Okay.
好的。
So we have Roman nose, somebody that has a long straight nose.
所以“高挺鼻”指的是有一个长而直的鼻子的人。
Now what about a pointy nose?
那“尖鼻子”呢？
A pointy nose means that the tip of the nose is pointy.
“尖鼻子”意味着鼻尖是尖的。
So maybe it goes up a little bit, goes down and then up.
所以可能它有点向上翘，先向下再向上。
But usually there's a point on the tip of the nose.
但通常鼻尖上有一个尖点。
Or sometimes the nose is very thin, right?
或者有时候鼻子很窄，对吧？
It's not very wide so it looks very pointy.
它不是很宽，所以看起来很尖。
That's right.
没错。
So it kind of gets very narrow at the end there.
所以它在末端变得很窄。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
And now maybe you broke your nose once or you had an accident and some people have a
现在，也许你曾经摔断过鼻子，或者出过事故，有些人会有
crooked nose.
一个歪鼻子。
Yeah, a lot of very famous football players have crooked noses because you get hit in
是的，很多著名的足球运动员都有歪鼻子，因为脸被足球击中，
the face with the football and then your nose always has a bump.
然后鼻子上总有一个凸起。
Something is crooked if it's not straight.
如果某物不直，那就是歪的。
So crooked is the opposite of a Roman nose or a straight nose.
所以“歪”是“高挺鼻”或“直鼻”的反义词。
That's right.
没错。
So maybe you see boxers also I think have crooked nose.
所以也许你看到拳击手也有歪鼻子。
Most of them are hockey players and stuff like that.
大多数是冰球运动员之类的。
Yeah, they take a lot of hits to the face.
是的，他们的脸经常被击中。
Okay, so now moving on that we've described noses in many ways.
好的，现在我们继续，我们已经用多种方式描述了鼻子。
You can say long nose, short nose or whatever but this is another way of doing it.
你可以说长鼻子、短鼻子等等，但这是另一种描述方式。
And what about eyebrows?
那眉毛呢？
Okay, eyebrows are those lines of hair above your eyes.
好的，眉毛是眼睛上方的那排毛发。
And some people have really thick eyebrows.
有些人有非常浓密的眉毛。
Some people have very thin eyebrows.
有些人有非常稀疏的眉毛。
But if someone has thick eyebrows, lots of hair, we call them bushy eyebrows.
但如果有人有浓密的眉毛，很多毛发，我们称之为“浓密眉毛”。
Okay.
好的。
So if you have bushy eyebrows, it means that you have a lot of hair as you said on your
所以如果你有“浓密眉毛”，意味着你有很多毛发，就像你说的，
eyebrows or over your eye.
在眉毛上或眼睛上方。
And now this is a really I think kind of a nice feature that some people have on their
现在，我觉得这是一个有些人脸上很不错的特征，
cheeks.
在脸颊上。
We have dimples.
我们有酒窝。
I love dimples.
我喜欢酒窝。
Not many people have them.
不是很多人有酒窝。
But these are two little dots, little indentations that appear when a person smiles.
但它们是两个小点，当一个人微笑时出现的小凹陷。
That's right.
没错。
Maybe you've seen this or maybe you have this or a friend has this.
也许你见过这个，或者你自己有，或者朋友有。
Somebody smiles and on their cheeks towards the middle of the cheek, they have little
有人微笑时，在他们的脸颊上，靠近脸颊中间的地方，会有小
holes that form that look like, I don't know, like somebody kind of pinched it with a needle.
洞形成，看起来就像，怎么说呢，像有人用针捏了一下。
Yeah, like it goes down a little bit for some reason.
是啊，就像不知为何凹下去一点。
It goes like yeah, they're being pinched inside their cheek.
就像，嗯，脸颊里面被捏了一下。
That's right.
没错。
Those are called dimples.
那些就叫酒窝。
Dimples.
酒窝。
Okay, so a lot of great stuff there in the first part.
好的，第一部分有很多精彩内容。
Let's review what we've heard.
我们来回顾一下听到的内容。
Let's go back to the dialogue and we'll be back in a bit.
我们回到对话，一会儿再回来。
Let's play a game.
我们来玩个游戏。
Okay.
好的。
How about Scrabble?
玩拼字游戏怎么样？
No, no.
不，不。
A friend of mine taught me this really fun game.
我朋友教了我一个很好玩的游戏。
I'm going to describe someone's face and you guess who it is.
我来描述一个人的脸，你猜是谁。
Okay.
好的。
Let's see.
让我想想。
He has a Roman nose, bushy eyebrows and dimples.
他有一个罗马鼻，浓密的眉毛和酒窝。
Our cousin Pete.
我们的表弟皮特。
My turn.
轮到我了。
She has a pointy nose, sunken eyes and a mole on her chin.
她有一个尖鼻子，凹陷的眼睛，下巴上有一颗痣。
Aunt Rose.
罗斯阿姨。
That mole is so huge.
那颗痣真大。
Okay, my turn.
好的，轮到我了。
He has a crooked nose and full lips.
他有一个歪鼻子和丰满的嘴唇。
He has quite a few freckles and an oval face.
他有很多雀斑，脸是椭圆形的。
Oh, he's also bald.
哦，他还是个光头。
Your future husband.
你未来的老公。
Not funny.
不好笑。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now we're going to take a look at even more words on how to describe a face.
所以现在我们要看看更多描述脸部的词汇。
So now let's take a look at Language Takeaway Part 2.
现在让我们看看“语言要点”第二部分。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Okay, so the first word has to do with the eyes.
好的，第一个词和眼睛有关。
We just talked about the eyebrows.
我们刚刚讨论了眉毛。
Those are above your eyes.
它们在眼睛上方。
Well, what happens if your eyes are very, very deep in your face?
那么，如果你的眼睛在脸上非常深，会怎么样？
Okay, we heard that in the dialogue.
好的，我们在对话中听到了这个。
We heard that in the dialogue described as sunken eyes.
我们在对话中听到它被描述为“凹陷的眼睛”。
So sunken means very far back or very deep in something.
所以“sunken”意思是某物非常靠后或非常深。
Think about a sunken ship.
想想一艘沉船。
It's under the water, under the ocean.
它在水下，在海洋下面。
So someone with sunken eyes probably has dark rings under their eyes because their eyes
所以有凹陷眼睛的人可能眼睛下有黑眼圈，因为他们的眼睛
are so deep in their head.
在头部里很深。
That's right.
没错。
And the opposite, maybe you've seen people that have eyes that are almost like popping
相反的情况，也许你见过有些人眼睛几乎像要
out a little bit.
突出来一点。
Right.
对。
His eyes pop out.
他的眼睛突出来。
That means they come out of the face.
意思是它们从脸上凸出来。
They're closer to the skin.
它们更靠近皮肤。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, and now this is something that many people have and even some models have become
好的，现在这个是很多人有的，甚至有些模特因为
famous because of this.
这个而出名。
Many times called a beauty mark.
很多时候被称为美人痣。
We're talking about moles.
我们在说痣。
Cindy Crawford is probably the model you're talking about.
辛迪·克劳馥大概就是你说的那个模特。
She had a very famous mole.
她有一颗非常著名的痣。
A mole is basically a spot on your skin that's very, very dark.
痣基本上是你皮肤上一个非常非常黑的斑点。
So sometimes there's hair on it.
所以有时候上面有毛。
Sometimes its texture is different.
有时候它的质地不同。
But it can be big, it can be small.
但它可以大，也可以小。
But it's a change of texture on your skin.
但它是你皮肤上质地的变化。
That's right.
没错。
So usually it's like a little brown ball if it's big.
所以通常如果它大，就像一个小棕色球。
And sometimes they just look like little spots on your skin, little dark brown spots.
有时候它们看起来就像皮肤上的小斑点，深棕色的小点。
That's right.
没错。
But they're not the same as something else we heard in today's dialogue.
但它们和我们今天对话中听到的另一个东西不一样。
So we'll wait for that.
所以我们等一下再说那个。
But a mole usually comes a little bit off the skin.
但痣通常稍微凸出皮肤一点。
And it's usually bigger than other dots.
而且通常比其他点大。
That's right.
没错。
And I think what you're talking about is freckles.
我想你说的是雀斑。
That's right, freckles.
没错，雀斑。
A lot of people have these when they're children.
很多人小时候都有这个。
They come on your nose and your cheeks and even your arms.
它们会长在鼻子、脸颊，甚至胳膊上。
And they're smooth with your skin.
它们和皮肤一样平滑。
They don't come off your skin.
它们不会从皮肤上脱落。
They're not puffy.
它们不是鼓起来的。
That's right.
没错。
And I think many of you maybe if you have lighter skin may have freckles.
我想你们中很多人，如果皮肤比较白，可能就有雀斑。
And that's usually just little spots but of just different color on your skin.
那通常只是皮肤上颜色不同的小点。
So usually people that have maybe red hair, they have freckles.
所以通常红头发的人会有雀斑。
Like maybe from the Harry Potter movie, Harry Potter's best friend, I think Ron.
比如《哈利·波特》电影里，哈利·波特最好的朋友，我想是罗恩。
Ron, yeah.
罗恩，对。
You can see he has freckles.
你可以看到他脸上有雀斑。
That's right.
没错。
On his skin he has lots of little dots.
他的皮肤上有很多小点。
Because he has very pale skin and red hair.
因为他皮肤很白，头发是红色的。
So these are called freckles.
这些就叫雀斑。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
And now when we talked about lips, a nice way of describing lips, you can say big lips
现在我们说到嘴唇，描述嘴唇的一个好方式，你可以说大嘴唇，
but that just means that they're big, right?
但那只是说它们很大，对吧？
But what about if that person has full lips?
但如果那个人有丰满的嘴唇呢？
Full lips is a great way to describe big lips.
丰满的嘴唇是描述大嘴唇的一个好说法。
We would say someone like Angelina Jolie has very full lips.
我们会说像安吉丽娜·朱莉这样的人有非常丰满的嘴唇。
That's right.
没错。
This means that they're not thin but they've got a lot of puff to them.
这意味着它们不薄，而且很有饱满感。
They have a lot of texture.
它们很有质感。
As you said, Angelina Jolie is probably the best example of someone with full lips.
就像你说的，安吉丽娜·朱莉可能是丰满嘴唇的最佳例子。
And now what about bald?
那秃头呢？
Someone who's bald.
一个秃头的人。
Who's a good example for this?
谁是个好例子？
Okay.
好的。
So this next word we've got is bald.
所以下一个词是秃头。
Who's a famous bald person?
谁是著名的秃头人物？
Maybe you've heard of Kobe Bryant.
你可能听说过科比·布莱恩特。
That basketball player.
那个篮球运动员。
That's right.
没错。
Now he's not completely bald.
他并不是完全秃头。
He actually shaves his head.
他其实是剃光了头。
But anyone who shaves their head also or has no hair on their head is considered to be
但任何剃光头或者头上没有头发的人都被认为是
a bald person.
秃头的人。
All right.
好的。
So bald means no hair on their head.
所以秃头意味着头上没有头发。
Right.
对。
Now sometimes naturally people become bald.
有时候人们会自然变秃。
Hair falls off as the years go by and no more hair grows on their head.
随着岁月流逝，头发脱落，头上不再长新头发。
So they're bald.
所以他们就秃了。
That's right.
没错。
So this happens to a lot of people, especially men.
这发生在很多人身上，尤其是男人。
They lose their hair.
他们掉头发。
Some people have a little bit of hair.
有些人还有一点头发。
Some people lose all of their hair.
有些人掉光了所有头发。
But when you lose hair on your head, it's called going bald.
但当你头上掉头发时，这叫做变秃。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So now we have a lot of words and how we can describe people.
现在我们有很多词来描述人。
And so why don't we go back, listen to the dialogue again, and we'll be back to talk
所以我们不如回去，再听一遍对话，然后我们回来再聊
a little bit more.
一点。
Let's play a game.
我们来玩个游戏。
Okay.
好的。
How about Scrabble?
玩拼字游戏怎么样？
No, no.
不，不。
A friend of mine taught me this really fun game.
我一个朋友教了我一个很好玩的游戏。
I'm going to describe someone's face and you guess who it is.
我来描述一个人的脸，你来猜是谁。
Okay.
好的。
Let's see.
让我想想。
He has a Roman nose, bushy eyebrows and dimples.
他有一个罗马鼻、浓密的眉毛和酒窝。
Our cousin Pete.
我们的表弟皮特。
My turn.
轮到我了。
She has a pointy nose, sunken eyes and a mole on her chin.
她有一个尖鼻子、凹陷的眼睛和下巴上的一颗痣。
Aunt Rose.
罗斯阿姨。
That mole is so huge.
那颗痣真大。
Okay.
好的。
My turn.
轮到我了。
He has a crooked nose and full lips.
他有一个歪鼻子和丰满的嘴唇。
He has quite a few freckles and an oval face.
他有很多雀斑和一张鹅蛋脸。
Oh, he's also bald.
哦，他还是个秃头。
Your future husband.
你未来的丈夫。
Not funny.
不好笑。
So we've talked a lot about the different parts of the face, but we have not talked
我们聊了很多关于脸的不同部位，但还没聊到
about one important part.
一个重要部分。
That's the bottom of a person's face along that bone there.
那是人脸底部沿着那块骨头的地方。
What's that part called?
那部分叫什么？
That's called the chin.
那叫下巴。
Okay.
好的。
So we could say some people have very, very prominent or big chins, right?
所以我们可以说有些人有非常突出或大的下巴，对吧？
Like for example, Jay Leno.
比如，杰·雷诺。
Oh yeah.
哦，是啊。
His chin is so big.
他的下巴真大。
It's almost a joke among people that he has this big chin.
他有个大下巴，这几乎成了人们之间的一个笑话。
That's right.
没错。
So he has a long chin.
所以他有个长下巴。
Now, other people may have a very square chin.
现在，其他人可能有非常方的下巴。
So it's almost like it looks like a square on the bottom of their face.
所以它看起来就像脸底部的一个方块。
Otherwise, you could have a round chin.
另外，你可能有个圆下巴。
That's right.
没错。
And the opposite part of the face is also very important.
而脸的另一部分也很重要。
We call it not the top of your head, but we call it your forehead.
我们不叫它头顶，而是叫它额头。
Your forehead.
你的额头。
Now, some people have a very big forehead, right?
现在，有些人有非常大的额头，对吧？
Because maybe their hair grows a little bit further back.
因为可能他们的头发长得稍微靠后一些。
And other people have smaller foreheads that you almost can't even really see.
而其他人有更小的额头，几乎看不见。
Or sometimes they just hide it with their hair.
或者有时他们只是用头发遮住它。
That's right.
没错。
And actually talking about chins, there's another type of chin that's also very popular.
实际上，说到下巴，还有另一种下巴也很常见。
John Travolta's chin.
约翰·特拉沃尔塔的下巴。
That is.
那是。
He has a dimple in his chin.
他下巴上有个酒窝。
That's right.
没错。
I remember we were talking about dimples, those little holes.
我记得我们之前聊过酒窝，那些小坑。
You can have them in other places and the chin is one of them.
你可以在其他地方有它们，下巴就是其中之一。
That's right.
没错。
So I think that's called a butt chin, if I'm not mistaken, right?
所以我想那叫屁股下巴，如果我没记错的话，对吧？
I'm not even going to ask.
我都不打算问了。
I've heard it before.
我以前听说过。
I'm not sure how to answer you, but yeah.
我不确定怎么回答你，但好吧。
So maybe this is a good time to encourage you all to tell us about your facial features
所以也许这是个好时机，鼓励大家告诉我们你的面部特征。
or to describe someone for us.
或者为我们描述某个人。
Use some of the vocabulary that you heard today.
用一些你今天听到的词汇。
That's right.
没错。
Or maybe you even just want to describe someone famous and we can guess who you're talking
或者你甚至只想描述某个名人，我们可以猜你在说谁。
about.
好挑战。
Good challenge.
So we will see you on our website, EnglishPod.com.
所以我们会在我们网站 EnglishPod.com 上见。
All right.
好的。
We'll see you guys there.
我们会在那里见你们。
Thanks very much for having us.
非常感谢你邀请我们。